# LinkedIn

# JAGADEESAN DEVAN

ADEESAN DE VAN

Github

Gitlab

13 Holland Drive, Singapore, 271013 Home: +65 98985208 jagadish.pd@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Engineering Leader with over 14+ years of experience in testing banking application, e-Commerce, handheld devices like Amazon Fire tablet, Kindle device, Game testing, social networking application, Web application, Video streaming application, Mobile application. Strong product development experience with background from top product-based companies like Amazon, Grab. Strong ability to manage software projects from concept to completion ensuring high quality software delivery.

### **SKILLS**

- Automation Tool: Selenium WebDriver, Testng, Appium, cypress, Cucumber, BDD Playwright, Rest Assured. Postman
- Performance Testing Tool: JMeter, Locust
- Webservice Testing: Postman, Rest Library
- Test Management Tool: Jira & Confluence, Redmine, Testlink, TestRail
- Essentials: GitHub, Gitlab, Docker
- Framework: Spring Boot
- Database: SQL, Dynamo DB, No SQL

- Languages: Java, Python, Shell, Java Script, Go, TypeScript, HTML
- OS: Windows, Linux, Apple OS, Ubuntu
- Cloud: AWS
- Platform: SAAS
- Messaging Services: Kafka, RabbitMQ
- Debugging Tools: Kibana, Scalar, Charles Proxy
- CI/CD: Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Gitlab CI/CD

# **Core Competence**

**Engineering Leadership & Team Management:** Build and lead high-performance QA engineering teams, overseeing projects with 50+ developers and quality engineers.

**Strategic Quality Assurance & Testing**: Design and implement comprehensive testing strategies that significantly reduce costs and improve product quality.

**Productivity Optimization**: Enhance engineering workflows and productivity through effective implementation of cutting-edge technologies and methodologies through implementing and tracking the DORA metrics

**Digital Transformation**: Drive enterprise-wide digital transformation projects, improving business processes and technological capabilities.

**Stakeholder Management & Training**: Develop strong client relationships, providing expert training and support to ensure alignment with business goals.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **DBS Bank (Contract)**

Singapore

QA Manager 10/2023 to Current

**Industry:** Finance

**Functional Areas:** CDD, KYC, Enterprise surveillance System, Compliance, Suspicious Activity Monitoring **Tech Stacks**: Actimize application, Cucumber BDD, Gherkin, React, Type Script, Mario DB, My Sql, Selenium, Rest Assured, JMETER, Locust, Postman

### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Quality Assurance Strategy: Develop and implement QA and test automation strategies aligned with the bank's objectives to improve test coverage, test efficiency and regulatory requirements. Establish and maintain quality standards for testing processes, ensuring adherence to best practices.
- Implemented a framework for tracking various QA metrics to measure the QA efficiency and product quality which helped to measure product quality and improve it via data driven metrics
- Have driven multiple interbank regulation related project from initiation till completion driving the QA program within bank.

- **Leadership & Mentorship:** Lead and mentor a team of 8 to 10 QA testers and Automation engineers supporting 50+, developers fostering a collaborative, high-performance culture. Conduct regular performance reviews and provide constructive feedback to support professional development
- **Automation Efficiency**: Spearhead the adoption of automated testing solutions using Selenium, Cucumber, Playwright improving efficiency and reducing manual effort. Built a Selenium-Cucumber Rest Assured framework for Web and API automation, automating 500+ test cases, reducing feature sign-off timelines by 40%.
- Leveraged DBS GPT tool to adopt and integrate GenAI solutions in testing practices and improve testing
  accuracy and productivity in test planning, test scenario enumeration and requirement scoring which
  contributed to test accuracy.
- Stakeholder Collaboration: Collaborate with internal vendor partners, product owners, developers, and other stakeholders to ensure alignment on testing requirements and timelines. Liaise with in house QA and vendor QA, TPM teams to manage timelines and prioritize releases.
- **Reporting & Documentation:** Prepare and present reports on testing progress, quality metrics, and automation initiatives to senior management. Maintain comprehensive documentation of testing processes, results, and automation workflows.

#### **GRAB HOLDING**

Singapore

**Lead QA Engineer** 07/2018 to 10/2023

Industry: Transport, Payment, Financial Service

**Tech Stacks**: Android, IOS, Go, AWS, Rabbitmq, Kafka, Redis, Dynamo DB, Gandalf tool, NodeJS, Selenium, Cypress, BDD, Cucumber, Appium, Python

### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Hired as 1st QA for Grab driver backend web service and came up with setting up process, concise test plan and writing test cases for 10 driver services.
- Tested Grab Payment system for KYC and CDD for Southeast Asia operating countries for name and payment screening using Actimize application.
- Tested Grab Pay wallet services and integration with third party service providers.
- Tested Grab driver mobile app on Android and IOS platform for different features catering to millions of customers by coming up with detailed test strategy.
- Worked on test-driven engineering culture with a team of front-end and back-end developers with a quality-first mindset emphasizing on good engineering practices.
- Automated 60% regression mobile app test case using Appium there by saving 70% of weekly manual effort.
- Collaborate with different teams for testing features and triage the bugs to help stakeholders make an informed decision of app release to AppStore.
- Actively involved in hiring and mentoring the QA team across Grab on testing and automation strategy.
- Conduct and provide knowledge sharing session among QA community.
- Organize exploratory testing session among QA community for key feature launch impacting millions of users.
- Automated 100% of driver web service smoke test in a time span of 4 months and integrated it to pipeline thereby eliminating manual QA work for sign off for deployment of service to production.
- Set up a selenium-based automation framework for the team and automated 100% of smoke test of driver onboarding portal thereby eliminating 100% manual efforts.
- Performed extensive user interface testing in mobile devices, including Android and iOS, performance testing of backend systems to identify performance bottlenecks.

# **WORKS APPLICATON**

Singapore

Senior Software QA Engineer
Industry: ERP product development

Project: HUE MAIL, HUE EC, HUE SCM

**Roles & Responsibilities:** 

- Reviewed Business requirements, software Design-documents and prepared Test Plans for all assigned project releases
- Performed functional testing across different browser and mobile platforms (IOS & Android)
- Improved test coverage by 60% applying testing principles to HUE EC product which impacted in finding new bugs.
- Reproduce the customer issues and help the support team by providing logs and assist them in functional understanding.
- Implemented a BDD UI Automation framework using Selenium, Cucumber for automation and automated 60% of regression test cases.
- Contributed to JMETER performance automation script by simulating load testing test case for HUE EC project.
- Contributed to REST API testing and automation using Postman and Rest Assured library.

#### **LEANSWIFT SOLUTIONS**

Chennai, TamilNadu

**Lead QA Engineer** 01/2015 to 07/2017

Industry: eCommerce consulting and ERP integration product development

Project: eConnect Webservice, Infor M3 Desktop application, Magento Web Application, Mobile First App

# **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Joined as 1st QA member of the organization and built a team of 6 members offering 50% productivity as an individual contributor after setting the team.
- Responsible for setting up the test process, procuring test tools, setting up the test environment in AWS, deployment of code.
- Implemented Page object pattern Selenium framework for UI automation and integrated test with Jenkins to run on a daily basis. Made team contribute to regression automation demonstrating solid ROI for automation project.
- Created performance script using JMETER to simulate load testing of eConnect web service and measured performance timelines.
- Conducted several brainstorming sessions with product managers, devs, and QEs to understand the scope of each
  feature, impact areas and technical complications that need to be considered while writing test plan and test
  cases.
- Triage bugs and manage projects by tracking using Jira and send out a status report to stakeholders.
- Coordinated resource allocations, created work assignments for the team, maintained timelines/milestones and ensured compliance with quality standards.

#### **AMAZON**

Chennai, TamilNadu

**QA Engineer** 07/2010 to 12/2014

Project: Fire OS (Customized Android OS), KDK Web Development, Amazon video

## **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Experience in testing Amazon handheld device like Kindle Fire Tablet, Kindle, Fire Mobile devices Operating system for 4 years.
- Worked on Game testing of premier apps from EA Sports and certifying to release it to the amazon app store.
- Functional testing of amazon video streaming application.
- Created and documented test plan, test cases, managed test runs
- Performed comparison testing of Amazon Android apps with IOS apps.
- Automated regression cases and integrated it to be part of daily build cycle which gave test case results using Python.
- Tested 3rd party apps for Android on FireOS and launched to amazon store.

08/2017 to 07/2018

EDUCATION AND TRAINING	
BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING	2010
Anna University, Chennai, TN, India	
CERTIFICATIONS	
ISTQB Testing certified.	
AWS Cloud Certified	